I'm going to ask and try to answer,
سأطرح أسئلة وأحاول الإجابة عليها،
in some ways, kind of an uncomfortable question.
أسئلة قد تكون غير مريحة نوعًا ما.
Both civilians, obviously, and soldiers
المواطنون والجنود طبعًا، كلاهما
suffer in war;
يعانون أثناء الحرب؛
I don't think any civilian has ever missed
لا أظن أن أي مواطن قد افتقد
the war that they were subjected to.
الحرب التي شُنّت عليه.
I've been covering wars for almost 20 years,
قضيت في تغطية الحروب حوالي 20 عامًا،
and one of the remarkable things for me
وأحد الأشياء البارزة بالنسبة لي
is how many soldiers find themselves missing it.
هو كيف أن العديد من الجنود ما زالوا يفتقدونها.
How is it someone can go through
كيف يمكن لشخص خاض
the worst experience imaginable,
أسوأ تجربة يمكن تخيلها،
and come home, back to their home,
ثم عاد، عاد إلى بيته،
and their family, their country, and miss the war?
إلى عائلته، وبلاده، أن يفتقد الحرب؟
How does that work? What does it mean?
كيف يعمل ذلك؟ وماذا يعنيه؟
We have to answer that question,
يجب علينا الإجابة عن هذا السؤال،
because if we don't, it'll be impossible
لأننا إن لم نفعل، سيكون من المستحيل
to bring soldiers back
أن نعيد الجنود
to a place in society where they belong,
إلى مكانهم في المجتمع حيث ينتمون،
and I think it'll also be impossible to stop war,
وأعتقد أنه سيكون من المستحيل أيضًا أن نوقف الحرب،
if we don't understand how that mechanism works.
إذا لم نفهم كيف تعمل تلك التقنية.
The problem is that war
المشكلة هي أن الحرب
does not have a simple, neat truth,
لا تملك حقيقة بسيطة واضحة،
one simple, neat truth.
حقيقة واحدة بسيطة وواضحة.
Any sane person hates war,
كل إنسان عاقل يكره الحرب،
hates the idea of war,
يكره فكرة الحرب،
wouldn't want to have anything to do with it,
ولا يريد أي شيء له علاقة بها،
doesn't want to be near it, doesn't want to know about it.
لا يريد أن يكون بالقرب منها، ولا أن يعرف عنها.
That's a sane response to war.
ذلك هو التجاوب العاقل مع الحرب.
But if I asked all of you in this room,
لكن لو سألت كل من يتواجد في هذه الغرفة،
who here has paid money
من سيدفع المال
to go to a cinema
ليذهب إلى السينما
and be entertained by a Hollywood war movie,
ويستمتع بمشاهدة فيلم حربي لهوليوود،
most of you would probably raise your hands.
أغلبكم على الأرجح سيرفع يده.
That's what's so complicated about war.
ذلك ما يجعل الحرب معقدة جدًا.
And trust me, if a room full of peace-loving people
ثقوا بي، حتى لو كانت غرفة مليئة بأشخاص محبين للسلام
finds something compelling about war,
فإنهم سيجدون شيئًا ملحا بخصوص الحرب،
so do 20-year-old soldiers
كذلك الجنود ذوو الـ 20 عامًا
who have been trained in it, I promise you.
الذين تدربوا فيها، أعدكم بذلك.
That's the thing that has to be understood.
ذلك هو ما ينبغي أن يُفهم.
I've covered war for about 20 years, as I said,
لقد قمت بتغطية الحروب لحوالي 20 سنة، كما ذكرت،
were with American soldiers in Afghanistan.
للجنود الأمريكيين في أفغانستان.
I've been in Africa, the Middle East,
لقد كنت في أفريقيا، والشرق الأوسط،
Afghanistan in the '90s,
وأفغانستان في التسعينات،
but it was with American soldiers in 2007, 2008,
لكن مع الجنود الأمريكيين في 2007، 2008،
that I was confronted with
واجهت آنذاك
very intense combat.
معركة عنيفة جدًا.
I was in a small valley called the Korengal Valley
كنت في وادي صغير يدعى وادي كورينقال
in eastern Afghanistan.
في شرق أفغانستان.
It was six miles long.
كان طوله 6 أميال.
There were 150 men of Battle Company in that valley,
كان هناك 150 رجلًا من شركة باتل في ذلك الوادي.
and for a while, while I was there,
لفترة من الوقت، عندما كنت هناك،
almost 20 percent of all the combat
حوالي 20 % من مجمل القتال
in all of Afghanistan was happening
في أفغانستان كان يحدث
in those six miles.
في تلك الستة أميال.
A hundred and fifty men were absorbing
150 رجلًا كانوا يستقبلون
almost a fifth of the combat for all of NATO forces
حوالي خُمس قتال قوات الناتو
in the country, for a couple months.
في تلك البلاد، ولعدة أشهر.
It was very intense.
كان عنيفا جدًا.
I spent most of my time at a small outpost
أمضيت أغلب وقتي في قاعدة صغيرة
called Restrepo.
تدعى ريستريبو.
It was named after the platoon medic
سميت بذلك نسبة إلى مسعف الفصيلة
that had been killed about two months into the deployment.
والذي قتل قبل شهرين من انتشار الجنود.
It was a few plywood B-huts
لقد كانت عبارة عن أكواخ خشبية
clinging to a side of a ridge,
معلقة على جانب مجموعة تلال،
and sandbags, bunkers, gun positions,
أكياس رمل، مخابئ وصناديق البنادق
and there were 20 men up there
كان هناك 20 رجلًا
of Second Platoon, Battle Company.
لفصيلة ثانية تابعة لشركة باتل.
I spent most of my time up there.
قضيت أغلب وقتي هناك.
There was no running water.
لم يكن هناك ماءٌ جار.
There was no way to bathe.
كان الاستحمام مستحيلًا.
The guys were up there for a month at a time.
هؤلاء الرجال كانوا هناك منذ شهر متواصل.
They never even got out of their clothes.
لم يقوموا أبدًا بتغيير ملابسهم.
They fought. The worked.
لقد قاتلوا. وعملوا.
They slept in the same clothes.
وناموا في نفس الملابس.
They never took them off, and at the end of the month,
لم يغيروها أبدًا، وفي نهاية ذلك الشهر،
they went back down to the company headquarters,
عادوا مرة آخرى إلى مقر الشركة،
and by then, their clothes were unwearable.
وعندها، كانت ملابسهم غير صالحة.
They burned them and got a new set.
فحرقوها واستلموا مجموعة جديدة.
There was no Internet. There was no phone.
لم يكن هنالك إنترنيت، ولا هاتف.
There was no communication with the outside world up there.
لم يكن هناك اتصال بالعالم الخارجي.
There was no cooked food.
لم يكن هناك طعام يُطبخ.
There was nothing up there
لم يكن هنالك شيء
that young men typically like:
كان أولائك الشبان:
no cars, no girls, no television, nothing
بلا سيارات ولا فتيات ولا تلفزيون ولا شيء
except combat.
ما عدا القتال.
Combat they did learn to like.
القتال الذي تعلموا الاعتياد عليه.
I remember one day, it was a very hot day
أتذكر يومًا، كان الجو حارًا جدًا
in the spring,
في فصل الربيع،
and we hadn't been in a fight
ولم نخض أي قتال
in a couple of weeks, maybe.
في حوالي الأسابيع تقريبًا.
Usually, the outpost was attacked,
عادةً، تُهاجم قاعدتنا،
and we hadn't seen any combat in a couple of weeks,
لكننا لم نخض أي معركة منذ أسابيع،
and everyone was just stunned
كان الجميع مصدومين
with boredom and heat.
من الملل والحر.
And I remember the lieutenant walking past me
كما أتذكر ذلك الملازم يمر من أمامي
sort of stripped to the waist.
وقد خلع قميصه إلى خصره،
It was incredibly hot.
كان الجو حارًا جدًا.
Stripped to the waist, walked past me muttering,
مر من أمامي وهو يتمتم،
"Oh God, please someone attack us today."
"يا رب، أرجو أن يهاجمنا أحد اليوم"
That's how bored they were.
كانوا ضجرين إلى ذلك الحد.
That's war too, is a lieutenant saying,
تلك هي الحرب أيضًا، أن يقول ملازم،
"Please make something happen
"أرجو أن يحدث شيئًا
because we're going crazy."
لأننا سوف نجن."
To understand that,
لفهم ذلك،
you have to, for a moment,
يجب عليك، وللحظة،
think about combat not morally --
أن تقكر في القتال لا أخلاقيًا،
that's an important job to do —
وتلك وظيفة مهمة عليك تأديتها،
but for a moment, don't think about it morally,
للحظة، لا تفكر في القصف أخلاقيًا،
think about it neurologically.
لكن فكر فيه عصبيًا.
Let's think about what happens in your brain
دعونا نفكر في ما يحدث داخل دماغك
when you're in combat.
عندما تكون في المعركة.
First of all, the experience
قبل كل شيء، التجربة
is very bizarre, it's a very bizarre one.
غريبة جدًا، تجربة غريبة جدًا.
It's not what I had expected.
لم تكن كما توقعتها.
Usually, you're not scared.
عادةً، لا يصيبك الخوف
I've been very scared in combat,
لقد كنت خائف جدا أثناء القتال،
but most of the time when I was out there,
لكن أغلب الوقت وعندما أكون خارجًا،
I wasn't scared.
لم أكن خائفا.
I was very scared beforehand
كنت خائفا جدًا سلفًا
and incredibly scared afterwards,
وخائفا جدًا بعدها،
and that fear that comes afterwards can last years.
وذلك الخوف الذي يأتي بعدها يستمر لسنوات.
I haven't been shot at in six years,
لم تُطلق النار علي منذ ست سنوات،
and I was woken up very abruptly this morning
لكن أيقظني فزعًا هذا الصبح
by a nightmare that I was being strafed by aircraft,
كابوس رأيت فيه طائرة تهاجمني،
six years later.
بعد ست سنوات.
I've never even been strafed by aircraft,
مع أني لم أُهاجم أبدًا بواسطة طيارة،
and I was having nightmares about it.
لكن تأتيني كوابيس عنها.
Time slows down.
الوقت يصبح أبطأ.
You get this weird tunnel vision.
تأتيك رؤية النفق الغريبة تلك.
You notice some details very, very, very accurately
تلاحظ بعض التفاصيل الدقيقة جدًا
and other things drop out.
والبعض الآخر يتلاشى.
It's almost a slightly altered state of mind.
إنها في الغالب تغير بسيط في حالة الوعي.
What's happening in your brain
ما يحدث في دماغك
is you're getting an enormous amount of adrenaline
أنك تنتج كمية ضخمة من الأدرينالين
pumped through your system.
تضخ خلال جسمك.
Young men will go to great lengths
على الشبان أن يحاولون جاهدين
to have that experience.
ليمتلكوا تلك الخبرة.
It's wired into us.
إنه شيء فطري فينا.
It's hormonally supported.
مدعوم من الهرمونات.
The mortality rate for young men in society
نسبة الوفيات بين الشباب في المجتمع
is six times what it is for young women
أعلى بست مرات منها بين الشابات
from violence and from accidents,
من العنف والحوادث،
just the stupid stuff that young men do:
تلك الأشياء الغبية التي يفعلها الشباب:
jumping off of things they shouldn't jump off of,
بالقفز من على أشياء لا يفترض بهم القفز من عليها،
lighting things on fire they shouldn't light on fire,
يشعلون النار في أشياء لا يفترض بهم إشعالها،
I mean, you know what I'm talking about.
أعني، أنتم تدركون ما أتحدث عنه.
They die at six times the rate
يموتون بمعدل ست مرات
that young women do.
أكثر من الشابات.
Statistically, you are safer as a teenage boy,
إحصائيًا، أنت بمأمن كفتى مراهق،
you would be safer in the fire department
ستكون بمأمن لو عملت في قسم الإطفاء
or the police department in most American cities
أو قسم الشرطة في أغلب المدن الأمريكية
than just walking around the streets of your hometown
أكثر من كونك تتجول في شوارع مدينتك
looking for something to do,
بحثًا عن شيء تفعله،
statistically.
إحصائيًا.
You can imagine how that plays out in combat.
تقدرون على التخيل كيف يطبق ذلك أثناء المعركة.
At Restrepo, every guy up there was almost killed,
في ريستريبو، كل رجل هناك كان على وشك أن يقتل،
including me,
بمن فيهم أنا،
including my good friend Tim Hetherington,
بمن فيهم صديقي العزيز تيم هيثرينقتون،
who was later killed in Libya.
الذي قُتل لاحقًا في ليبيا.
There were guys walking around
كان هناك رجال يمشون
with bullet holes in their uniforms,
وآثار الرصاص على زيّهم العسكري،
rounds that had cut through the fabric
دوائر اخترقت ومزقت القماش
and didn't touch their bodies.
ولم تلامس أجسادهم.
I was leaning against some sandbags one morning,
ذات صباح كنت أتكئ على بعض أكياس الرمل
not much going on, sort of spacing out,
لم يكن يحدث شيء، كان نوعا من السَرَحان
and some sand was kicked into the side of,
بدأ بعض الرمل يتطاير على جانب وجهي،
sort of hit the side of my face.
يضرب نوعًا ما جانب وجهي.
Something hit the side of my face, and I didn't know what it was.
شئ ما ضرب جانب وجهي، ولم أكن أعرف ما هو.
You have to understand about bullets
يجب أن تفهموا بأن الرصاص
that they go a lot faster than sound,
ينطلق أسرع من الصوت،
so if someone shoots at you
فإذا أطلق أحدهم باتجاهك
from a few hundred meters,
من على بُعد بضع مئات الأمتار،
the bullet goes by you, or hits you obviously,
ستمر الرصاصة بجانبك، أو قد تضربك
half a second or so before the sound catches up to it.
بالتأكيد قبل أن يصل صوتها بحوالي نصف الثانية.
So I had some sand sprayed in the side of my face.
انتشر بعض الرمل على جانب وجهي.
Half a second later, I heard dut-dut-dut-dut-duh.
بعدها بنصف ثانية،سمعت دو - دو - دو - دو - دو.
It was machine gun fire.
لقد كان مدفعا رشاشا.
It was the first round, the first burst
كانت أول جولة، أول انفجار
of an hour-long firefight.
من ساعة متواصلة من إطلاق النار.
What had happened was the bullet hit,
ما حدث هو أن الرصاصة ضربت،
a bullet hit three or four inches from the side of my head.
الرصاصة ضربت 3 إلى 4 إنشات من جانب رأسي.
Imagine, just think about it, because I certainly did,
تخيلوا، فقط فكروا في الأمر، لأنني بالتأكيد فكرت،
think about the angle of deviation that saved my life.
فكروا في زاوية الانحراف التي أنقذت حياتي.
At 400 meters, it missed me by three inches.
من على بعد 400 متر، أخطأتني فقط بثلاث إنشات.
Just think about the math on that.
فقط فكروا حسابيًا في ذلك.
Every guy up there
كل رجل هناك
had some experience like that,
لديه تجربة شبيهة بهذه،
at least once, if not many times.
واحدة على الأقل، إن لم يكن أكثر.
The boys are up there for a year.
الشبان تواجدوا هناك لسنوات.
They got back.
ثم عادوا.
Some of them got out of the Army
بعضهم ترك الجيش
and had tremendous psychological problems when they got home.
وتعرض لمشاكل نفسية هائلة عندما عاد إلى البلاد.
Some of them stayed in the Army
والبعض الآخر بقي في الجيش
and were more or less okay, psychologically.
وكانوا إلى حد ما بخير، نفسيًا.
I was particularly close to a guy named Brendan O'Byrne.
كنت مقرب بالتحديد إلى شخص يدعى بريندان أوبارني.
I'm still very good friends with him.
ومازالت تجمعنا صداقة جيدة جدًا.
He came back to the States. He got out of the Army.
عاد إلى الولايات المتحدة، وغادر الجيش.
I had a dinner party one night.
أقمت حفلة عشاء ذات ليلة.
I invited him,
ودعوته،
and he started talking with a woman,
وبدأ بالحديث مع إمرأة،
one of my friends,
واحدة من صديقاتي،
and she knew how bad it had been out there,
تعرف تمامًا سوء الأحوال هناك،
and she said, "Brendan,
قالت: "بريندان،
is there anything at all that you miss about
هل هناك أي شيء ما زلت تفتقده
being out in Afghanistan, about the war?"
في أفغانستان، في الحرب؟"
And he thought about it quite a long time,
وقد فكر في الأمر طويلًا،
and finally he said, "Ma'am, I miss almost all of it."
ثم قال، "سيدتي، أنا أفتقد تقريبًا كل شيء."
And he's one of the most traumatized people
وقد كان واحدا من أكثر الأشخاص المتضررين
I've seen from that war.
قد رأيت ذلك في الحرب.
"Ma'am, I miss almost all of it."
"سيدتي، أنا أفتقد تقريبًا كل شيء."
What is he talking about?
ماذا كان يقصد؟
He's not a psychopath.
لم يكن مختلًا عقليًا.
He doesn't miss killing people.
لم يفتقد قتل البشر.
He's not crazy. He doesn't miss getting shot at
لم يكن مجنونًا، لم يفتقد أن يطلق عليه النار
and seeing his friends get killed.
وأن يرى أصدقاءه يقتلون.
What is it that he misses? We have to answer that.
ماذا كان يفتقد؟ من سيجيب على ذلك.
If we're going to stop war, we have to answer that question.
إذا أردنا أن نوقف الحرب، يجب أن نجيب على هذا السؤال.
I think what he missed is brotherhood.
ما أعتقد أنه يفقتده هو الأخوة.
He missed, in some ways,
هو يفتقد، في بعض الأحيان،
the opposite of killing.
ما هو عكس القتل.
What he missed was connection
ما يفتقده هو الترابط
to the other men he was with.
مع الرجال الآخرين الذين كانوا معه.
Now, brotherhood is different from friendship.
الأخوة مختلفة عن الصداقة.
Friendship happens in society, obviously.
الصداقة تحدث في المجتمع، بكل وضوح.
The more you like someone,
كلما أعجبك شخص ما،
the more you'd be willing to do for them.
كلما وددت أن تفعل شيئا من أجله.
Brotherhood has nothing to do
الأخوة لا علاقة لها
with how you feel about the other person.
بما تشعر به تجاه الشخص الآخر.
It's a mutual agreement in a group
هي اتفاق فطري بين مجموعة
that you will put the welfare of the group,
على أن تضع مصلحة المجموعة،
you will put the safety of everyone in the group
وأن تضع أمان كل من في المجموعة
above your own.
فوق مصلحتك وأمانك.
In effect, you're saying,
عمليًا، كأنك تقول،
"I love these other people more than I love myself."
"أنا أحب هؤلاء الأشخاص أكثر من حبي لنفسي."
Brendan was a team leader
بريندان كان قائد فريق
in command of three men,
يقود ثلاثة رجال،
and the worst day in Afghanistan —
وفي أسوأ الأيام في أفغانستان،
He was almost killed so many times.
كان على وشك أن يقتل عدة مرات.
It didn't bother him.
لم يكترث لذلك.
The worst thing that happened to him in Afghanistan
أسوأ أمر حدث له في أفغانستان
was one of his men was hit in the head with a bullet
هو أن واحد من رجاله ضُرب برصاصة في رأسه
in the helmet, knocked him over.
ضربت الخوذة، وأسقطته أرضًا.
They thought he was dead.
أعتقدوا أنه قد مات.
It was in the middle of a huge firefight.
كان وسط معركة كبرى من إطلاق النيران.
No one could deal with it, and a minute later,
لم يقدر أحد على أن يتعامل معه، بعدها بدقيقة،
Kyle Steiner sat back up
نهض كايل ستاينر
from the dead, as it were,
من الموت، إن جاز التعبير،
because he'd come back to consciousness.
لأنه عاد مرة أخرى إلى وعيه.
The bullet had just knocked him out.
الرصاصة فقط أفقدته الوعي.
It glanced off the helmet.
صدتها الخوذة.
He remembers people saying,
تذكر الناس يقولون،
as he was sort of half-conscious,
بينما كان شبه فاقد للوعي،
"Steiner's been hit in the head. Steiner's dead."
"ستاينر ضُرب في رأسه، ستاينر قُتل."
And he was thinking, "I'm not dead."
وقد كان تفكيره، "أنا لست ميتًا."
And he sat up.
عندها استيقظ.
And Brendan realized after that
أدرك بريندان بعدها أنه
that he could not protect his men,
لم يستطع حماية رجاله،
and that was the only time he cried in Afghanistan,
وقد كانت تلك هي المرة الوحيدة التي بكى فيها في أفغانستان،
was realizing that.
عندما أدرك ذلك.
That's brotherhood.
تلك هي الأخوة.
This wasn't invented recently.
لم تكن قد أُخترعت حديثًا.
Many of you have probably read "The Iliad."
أكثركم قد قرأ "الإلياذة" على الأرجح.
Achilles surely would have risked his life
قد ضحى أخيل بالتأكيد بحياته
or given his life to save his friend Patroclus.
أو أعطى حياته ليحمي صديقه باتروكلوس.
In World War II, there were many stories
في الحرب العالمية الثانية، كان هناك الكثير من القصص
of soldiers who were wounded,
لجنود كانوا قد أصيبوا،
were brought to a rear base hospital,
وأحضروا إلى قاعدة طبية في الخلف،
who went AWOL,
خرجوا بلا إذن،
crawled out of windows, slipped out doors,
خرجوا من النوافذ، وتسللوا من الأبواب،
went AWOL, wounded,
خرجوا بلا إذن، جرحى،
to make their way back to the front lines
ليعودوا بأنفسهم مرة آخرى للصفوف الأولى
to rejoin their brothers out there.
لينضموا إلى أخوتهم هناك.
So you think about Brendan,
فكروا في بريندان،
you think about all these soldiers
وفكروا في كل هؤلاء الجنود
having an experience like that, a bond like that,
وهم يخوضون تجربة كتلك، رابطة كتلك،
in a small group,
في مجموعة صغيرة،
where they loved 20 other people
حيث أحبوا 20 شخصًا آخرين
in some ways more than they loved themselves,
بطريقة أكثر من حبهم لأنفسهم،
you think about how good that would feel, imagine it,
فكروا كيف سيكون ذلك الشعور، تخيلوه،
and they are blessed with that experience for a year,
وقد غُمروا بتلك التجربة لعام واحد،
and then they come home,
بعدها عادوا لبلادهم،
and they are just back in society
وعادوا ببساطة للمجتمع
like the rest of us are,
كبقيتنا،
not knowing who they can count on,
لا يعرفون من يعتمدون عليه،
not knowing who loves them, who they can love,
لا يعرفون من يحبهم، أو من يستطيعون محبته،
not knowing exactly what anyone they know
لا يعرفون تمامًا ما قد يفعله أي شخص يعرفونه لهم
would do for them if it came down to it.
عندما يحال الأمر إليه.
That is terrifying.
ذلك مرعب.
Compared to that,
مقارنة بذلك،
war, psychologically, in some ways, is easy,
الحرب، نفسيًا، من بعض النواحي، سهلة،
compared to that kind of alienation.
مقارنة بذلك النوع من العزلة.
That's why they miss it,
ذلك سبب افتقداهم لها،
and that's what we have to understand
وذلك ما يجب علينا أن نفهمه
and in some ways fix in our society.
وأن نصلحه من بعض النواحي في مجتمعنا.
Thank you very much.
شكرًا جزيلًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)